Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/naikkrish (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Data Science
Convolutional neural network
Machine Learning

Languages

Hindi

English

Kannada

Nepali

Publications

Hands-On Python for Finance: A practical guide to implementing financial analysis strategies using Python

Krish Naik

Youtuber (960K+ Subscribers)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Summary

Proven IT Professional with experience of 9 + years in Software Development & Project Implementation and 6 + years and currently working as a Lead Data Scientist Machine Learning & Deep Learning Developer. Possess widespread and progressive experience in the IT industry, focusing on business analysis, design, development, implementation and migration of large-scale, big budget business transformation projects. Impeccable knowledge for initiating applications with Algorithms, Data structures, Binary tree, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Convolutional Neural Network, Recurrent Neural Network, and Software Development & Project Implementation.

Currently Spear Heading as a Technical Lead with Honeywell Technology Solution, Bangalore, India. Actively contributes in conducting expert business & systems analysis, identifying business improvements & information systems solutions, coordinating & scheduling projects, developing & monitoring project plans, and managing the end-to-end delivery of projects

Experience

YouTube

Youtuber(960k+ subscribers)
December 2018 - Present (5 years 7 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

iNeuron.ai

Co-Founder

October 2020 - June 2024 (3 years 9 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Panasonic India

Lead Data Scientist

January 2019 - September 2020 (1 year 9 months)

Bangalore

Involved in Data Preprocessing Techniques for making the data useful for creating Machine

Learning models

- # Owned and executed end to end multiple data science projects
- # Translate product requirements into analytical requiremnets/specification, design and develop

required functionality.

- # Leveraged technology to automate daily operational activities.
- # Lead and mentor a team of students in my final year.
- # Involved in creating various regression and classification algorithms by using various sklearn

libraries such as Linear Regression, Decision Trees, Naïve Baye's

Involved in creating Machine Learning models for test A/B content which is useful for making

better decisions regarding the products

- # Also provided training within the college for Data Science, ML and Deep Learning.
- # Own a Youtube with 240k+ subscribers
- # Blogger for sharing Data Science related technolofies in Medium, TowardsData Science
- # Involved in designing the neural networks using Tensorflow for various internal projects within

the company such as automated chatbots using NLP

EY

Lead Data Scientist

September 2018 - January 2019 (5 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Honeywell

Tech Lead

December 2017 - September 2018 (10 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

Adroit in Python with libraries such as Sklearn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Tableau for Data Visualization, Keras, Tensorflow, C#,ASP.NET MVC, Sitecore CMS, Solr 5.5.1,MVC, SQL Server, AJAX, XML & Microsoft Cognitive Services

Proficiently handled some internal projects using tools such as Tableau for data visualization and reporting the product owner

- # Deft in managing all phases of the software development life-cycle (requirements, design, development, testing, release, support), utilizing multiple development methodologies, including design patterns, OOD, extreme programming, and structured programming
- # Professionally initiating Data Pre-processing Techniques for making the data useful for creating Machine Learning models
- # Imparts corporate training on Machine Learning and AI
- # Developing & executing end to end multiple data science projects
- # Translating product requirements into analytical requirements/specification, design and development required functionality
- # Awarded a book contract on python with Finance with deep Learning

Publicis Sapient

Senior Associate

April 2014 - December 2017 (3 years 9 months)

Bangalore

Sitecore CMS,Machine Learning, ASP .net MVC ,Data Science,Python,Spark,Sklearn,Numpy,Seaborn,MAtplotLib

HCL Technologies

Software Engineer

December 2011 - April 2014 (2 years 5 months)

- # Delivering and implementing the project as per scheduled milestones.
- Participating in Onsite deployment, customer support and product upgradation.
- # Interacting with the onshore team for requirements gathering, analysis, and implementations.
- # Structural designing & coding of solution for developing new applications.
- # Designing, coding and validating forms; coding programs and finally integrating them.

Education

PDA College of Engineering

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Science · (2007 - 2011)